Matthew Spaulding

Full Stack Developer

2584 Brandywine Dr. Clearwater, FL 33761 (727) 324-8369 mail@mattspaulding.org

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with over ten years of experience. Proven success in building software applications from conception to completion. Mentors and peer reviews junior developers. Active member of the development community, contributing to open source on GitHub with a Stack Overflow reputation of over 22K. Volunteers regularly as a sensei at the Coder Dojo, teaching kids how to code.

EXPERIENCE

LoanLogics, Jacksonville FL (Remote) — *Angular Architect*

OCT 2018 - PRESENT

- Architected v1.0 of the client side of an automated loan application.
- Created a reactively smooth interface using NgRx.
- Peer reviewed a team of developers.
- Tested code with Jasmine and Karma.

iProcedures, Tampa FL (Remote) — Angular Architect

MAR 2016 - OCT 2018

- Architected v1.0 of a cloud-based mobile Anesthesia Information Management System (AIMS).
- Developed a real-time vitals monitor using the D3.js charting library.
- Created Windows and Mac desktop applications using Electron.
- Automated versioning and deployment system to deliver updates to clients.
- Peer reviewed junior developers using the Gitflow workflow

Toptal, San Francisco CA (Remote) — Web Developer

SEPT 2015 - MAR 2016

Bubble's University - Angular Developer

- A children's learning platform.
- Developed a child-usable experience.
- link

Herndonwood Associates - .Net Developer

- Created ReKoN, a risk management platform for banking institutions.
- Implemented Azure as the cloud server and storage solution.
- Created a multi-level role system.

SOCIAL PROFILES

MattSpaulding.org

Stack Overflow

Github

SKILLS

Angular

Typescript

Javascript

NgRx/RxJS

HTML

SCSS

Node

Mongo

Express

C#

Web API

Entity Framework

Material Design

Bootstrap

Electron

NATIONALITY

US Citizen

Wolters Kluwer Law & Business, Tampa FL (Remote) — .Net Developer

JAN 2014 - SEPT 2015

- Developed a medical coding suite.
- Built a tool that uses fuzzy logic to find ICD10 codes.
- Built in the Azure cloud.

Mad Mobile, Tampa FL — Windows 8 Developer

NOV 2012 - OCT 2013

- Built the Office Depot Windows Store app.
- Created an eCommerce Windows app for a major online retailer.
- Connected to a custom API developed by Office Depot.
- Allowed users to see special deals, read product reviews, and add items to their cart.
- Displayed closest store by using geolocation.

Agile Thought, Tampa FL — .Net Developer

AUG 2012 - NOV 2012

• Built risk analysis software for Price Waterhouse Cooper

Mad Mobile, Tampa FL — .Net Developer

DEC 2011 - AUG 2012

- Converted several eCommerce websites into mCommerce mobile websites.
- Scraped HTML from the websites and presented the data as JSON through a RESTful .Net Web API.
- Architected an extensible application core used as the base for all of the mobile sites.

Enporion, Tampa FL — Adobe Flex Developer

JAN 2011 - DEC 2011

• Developed an online reverse auction website for municipality utilities.

Raytheon, Largo FL — Basic Developer

MAY 2009 - JULY 2010

- Developed a tool to automate calibration of electrical equipment in Basic. (Voltameter, oscilloscope, etc.)
- The tool shrunk a 6 hour calibration process down to ten minutes.

EDUCATION

University of South Florida, Tampa FL Master of Science in Computer Engineering

2011

GPA: 3.25

Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society President

PUBLICATIONS

Build Ultra-Modern Web Apps with Angular Material

2016

Material Design uses a paper metaphor, bold intentions, and meaningful motion to give user interfaces an ultra-modern feel. Web applications built using AngularJS can now easily adopt these design principles using Angular Material, a reference implementation of Google's Material Design Specification.

link

A Dynamic Hierarchical Web-Based Portal (Master Thesis)

2011

A dynamic hierarchical web-based portal was created to house a suite of web-based supply chain management applications. The portal was designed in a hierarchical manner to match the structure of large companies. Administrators of the portal have the ability to form the portal in such a way to mimic the existing structure of their company.

link

PERSONAL PROJECTS

GIVVN

- A tool for helping nonprofit organizations collect donations.
- Uses Natural Language Processing (NLP) to automate interactions.
- link

FreeStock

- A collection of bots that manage your stock portfolio.
- Stock picks based on historical trend analysis.
- link

Angular Material Kitchen Sink

- Everything Angular Material... everything but the kitchen sink.
- An open-source AngularJS project, Angular Material is the reference implementation of Google's Material Design Specification.
- This project provides a fully-functioning AngularJS project showcasing UI components based on Material Design.
- link

Blrbr (Deprecated)

- Push-to-talk for Twitter.
- An iPhone and Android mobile app that turns your phone into a social WalkieTalkie.